Robert Rocco Basso

(978) 504-1244 ■ robertbasso2@gmail.com ■ 20 Bay Street, Amesbury MA, 01913

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with experience designing scalable and resilient backends via indexing, eager loading, multi-level data validation, database normalization/denormalization, and cacheing; and responsive frontends with media queries, SCSS variables and mixins, and AJAX requests.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, ActiveRecord, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Java, Eclipse, C#, SQL, Heroku, PostgreSQL, ReactJS, Git, Github, Foundation, Bootstrap, RSpec, Capybara, MiniTest, Puma, AWS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Dollarship

Boston, MA

Software Engineer

Apr. 2017 - Aug. 2017

Core API

- Created data objects from all with database and model level data validation, indexing, both singular & compound, when speed or uniqueness was required, and polymorphic classes where necessary
- Implemented CRUD functionality around data models often involving custom SQL and database joins
- Wrote unit tests to ensure all code was high quality and sustainable
- Developed scoped controllers to guarantee only verified users/admin could access proprietary data

Admin Console

- Designed UI for admin to export sweepstakes data into a CSV, add mail in users, and add spending thresholds for bonus credits
- Utilized PropTypes validations to alert future developers and users if required data was missing

Cannonball Email

Boston, MA

Software Engineer

Sept. 2015 – Mar. 2017

MyBlendApp

- Designed responsive front end that retained the user interface on screen sizes ranging from smart phones to computer displays
- Incorporated back end features such as AJAX requests for "Up Next" content, infinite scrolling functionality, filtering by keywords or topic, and displaying of personal emails for registered users

Customer Relationship Manager

- Implemented caching mechanism to store the IDs of articles recommended for a particular user to mitigate loading time
- Employed database denormalization to minimize response times

PROJECTS

Park Easy

- Implemented custom JavaScript and jQuery to give users several methods to add parking areas to the map, open index menus, etc.
- Integrated with Google, Facebook, and Twitter OAuth to give users multiple login options

ShowUp

- Integrated with Spotify API to provide song previews and album artwork for each concert listing
- Utilized ActiveRecord eager loading to improve rendering time of the index page

EDUCATION Boston, MA

Northeastern University

Sept. 2009 - June 2014

B S Mathematics

Minor Computer Science